Ashionye Onwuka

Calgary, AB • 587-966-8967 • ashionyeo@yahoo.com • linkedin.com/in/Ashionye

Summary

Tech-savvy and adaptable professional with 5+ years of international experience and a proven knowledge in application development, networking, system architecture and diagnostics, managing permission, configuration management, and database design. Hardworking with good workflow prioritization and process management. Self-motivated and open to new challenges, and able to work alone or in a team.

Skills

Technology: Back-End and Database, Python, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, JQuery, Git, React, Express, SQL, Azure, AWS, Cloud Computing, SNMP Monitoring, TCP/IP, Cisco Networking, Windows Server, Software Installation, Multiprotocol Label Switching (MPLS), Internet and Email.

Application: Scratch, Figma, Firebase, Microsoft Power Apps, Mocha, Chai, MS OneSupport Dynamics 365, Windows, Outlook, Zoom, Teams, Microsoft Office Suite, Google Workspace, AVD, SolarWinds, tawk.to, Google Maps, Citrix client, Huawei iManager M2000, Ericsson OSS, and BMS Remedy software.

Personal: Highly Analytic, Meticulous Attention to Detail, Leadership, Organised, Time Management, Emotional Intelligence, Problem-solving, Critical Thinking, Creativity and Innovation, Accountability, Technical Writing, Coding, Effective Communication, and People Management.

Employment

Full-stack Web Development Student

Oct 2022 - Apr 2023

Making Changes Association • Calgary

- Create front-end and back-end applications with React Native, including software testing techniques.
- Identify and fix bottlenecks and bugs.
- Engage in weekly code reviews to check code quality and system performance.

Technical Support Engineer

Nov 2021 - Sep 2022

Tek Experts • Lagos

- Delivered advanced technical troubleshooting and problem-solving solutions for service issues related to Microsoft Azure Firewall, Virtual Networks, VPN gateway, Application gateway, Bastion, virtual WAN, and Load balancers.
- Collaborated with subject matter experts and escalation managers when additional support is needed, while analysing service logs and packet captures.
- Managed critical issues by setting customer expectations, devising and implementing action plans, and professionally communicating to all parties involved.

Support Officer

Jul 2020 - Jan 2021

VDT Communications Limited • Lagos

- Managed communication with clients and colleagues to gain an adequate understanding of clients' inquiries or complaints to ensure clients' and organization expectations are exceeded.
- Fixed support requests from end-users and patiently walked individuals through basic troubleshooting tasks and repairs, utilizing problem-solving skills and communications skills.

 Proposed and implemented system enhancements to improve performance and reliability of customer success.

Incident Manager

Jun 2019 - Oct 2019

Huawei Technologies Nigeria Limited • Lagos

- Provided immediate emergency response and incident management by assessing incident priority based upon impact to the business and achieved excellent lead time in tackling incidents, optimization, and KPI improvement.
- Improved network performance compared to threshold availability with proper incident follow-ups and incident resolution, oversaw scheduled infrastructure upgrades and integration, and made quick decisions in an effort to reduce overall network impact.
- Supervised and assisted technical upgrade projects to support teams, report progress, and influence positive outcomes for key stakeholders; by working and coordinating with radiofrequency, optics, transmission, and BSS teams.

NOC Support Engineer

Apr 2016 - Jun 2019

Huawei Technologies Nigeria Limited • Lagos

- Monitored and maintained network and software components according to established guidelines, best practices, and SLA.
- Diagnosed network problems involving a combination of hardware, software, power, and communications issues with enhanced network performance to drive efficiency.
- Installed OS patches, firewalls, anti-virus definition updates, and network monitoring solutions to ensure 99% network uptime.

Education

MSC Computer Network and Security

Oct 2014 - Sep 2015

University of Essex • Colchester

BENG Electrical/Electronics Engineering

Dec 2007 - Nov 2012

University of Benin • Benin City

Certifications and Trainings

•	Full-Stack Web Development with Python Programming Course	Mar 2023
•	Microsoft Certified: Azure Network Engineer Associate	May 2022
•	Microsoft Certified: Azure Administrator Associate	Mar 2022
•	AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner	Jan 2022
•	CCNAv7: Introduction to Networks Course	Sep 2021
•	Jobberman Accelerated Soft Skills Course	Aug 2021
•	Google IT Support Professional	Mar 2021
•	Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals	Jan 2021

Accomplishments

- Awarded Quality Assurance, QA Hero of the month for the excellent evaluation score and outstanding customer interaction skills, while working with Tek Experts.
- Recognised for drafting VDT devices' FAQs, to grow the effectiveness of the client support team.
- Selected amongst my peers to lead the team in Huawei as the incident manager.